Generation technology. So I work in new energy school at North China Electric University. So
my topic is about new energy. Okay. So first, actually, I will also have a very short
introduction for myself. I had my master and PhD in Chile University in China. And I also was
I was a joint PhD student at the University of Bristol in the UK.
Now I am a professor at the North China Electric Power University in Beijing.
And this is my other work experience.
I was an academic visitor at Northwestern University in the USA,
and I did some research collaborations with Australia, Russia, Kazakhstan,
Kazakhstan, these universities as well, like South Europe, State University in Russia.
I don't know, you guys come from Russia, a country from which university?
And also Northwestern University, University of New South Wales in Australia, and Nazarbayev
University in Kazakhstan as well.
Okay, alright, so the first topic actually is about technology pathways for new energy
power generation because my 50 slides is too much I have to finish it within like
1 hour and 10 so I will speak a little bit fast okay so we just finished our
14th five-year plan during the year of 2021 to 2025 what we achieved in here we
installed capacity double like total installed capacity of new energy reached
reached almost 2 million kilowatt hours, and it's including wind power for about 640 gigawatts,
and for solar power, around 1,200 gigawatts, and biomass is less one, it's like 47 gigawatts.
And also for green electricity consumption grows steadily, in the last year, the newly
added renewable energy generated amount to 590 billion kilowatts hour which
already covered the increase in total electricity consumption of the whole
society okay so here this is our new dual carbon goals we proposed it in the
year of 2020 in December so it's including like we have to achieve carbon
peak before the year of 2030 and carbon neutrality before 2016. After we proposed
these dual carbon goals, what we've done is from here, okay, we can see the data in
here from the year of 2020 to the last year. The obvious one is for solar power
in stored capacity. It's increased very fast. And then after that is wind power in stored
capacity the last one is biomass unfortunately we can see from the curves
it's like very steady growth right we don't have very satisfied data for
biomass so I'm not talking about very detailed thing about biomass today but
mainly about wind power and solar okay what's going on all right so now we
start with 15th five-year plan which is started from the year of 2026 so our
goals are like building a new energy system we will develop major hydropower
projects as well and integrated hydropower wind solar basis so we're
going to combine all this new energy together as well as new energy in
different bases like desert, goby and barren lands and also offshore wind power
bases which we visited yesterday all right and the second one is like
rigorously building a new type power system it's like construct smart grids
which I will talk about later and the improve urban and rural distribution
networks scientifically deploy pumped storage hydroelectricity and vigorously
develop new type energy storage. The third is basically completing a unified
electricity market system like expand cross provisional and cross regional
electricity trading. Actually this is very important for my hometown because
my hometown is in the west of China and we have less people over there but we
we have lots of lands over there that we can use,
and improve ancillary service markets
and capacity markets,
and scale up green electricity trading
and green certificate trading.
This is data from last year for the share of new energy.
This is pie chart, we can see from solar PV,
it's the largest one,
and then coming up is wind power,
and for biomass it's still the lowest one. The second point is about the new
energy power generation routes. For example, for wind power generation, the
newly installed capacity in the year of 2020 is around 72 million kilowatts
hour, kilowatts sorry, and it's grown up to 120 million in the year of 2025. It's
pretty high right and characteristics is like we have significant economies of
scale for solar sorry for wind power and good land competitive compatibility and
no water consumption but the disadvantages is like fluctuating and
intermittent and high site requirements but for solar power we can see it's
increased from 48 million kilowatts in the year of 2020 okay it don't work to 318 million kilowatts
in the year of 2025 it's like a very huge and fast growth and it has abundant life resources
in china and a wide range of application scenarios and short conduction construction cycle but the
The disagreement still seems, right, it's like highly intermittent as well, and significantly affected by dust.
The last one is biomass.
So unfortunately, we can see it's decreased from 5 to 1, 1.5 million kilowatt hours.
But the good thing is we still reuse for biomass energy and good, very good stability as well.
for disadvantages it's like it has low fuel low fuel density and fuel gas
requires environmentally friendly treatment the third point is about the
technology especially wind power technology we have these four different
stages for the first stage it's in the last century so we use the turbine is
like the fixed ones fixed pitch store regulated wind turbine and we use this
squirrel cage induction generator can you imagine squirrel cage I don't know
if you guys see the squirrel cage so the drive tree is like squirrel cage induction
generator with gearbox and for the materials normally we use glass fiber
reinforced and the tower is not that high it's like less than 40 meters but
in the second stage we can see that the turbine changed it's from the fixed
change to variable pitch technology so it's a little bit more flexible and for
drivetrain we use jobless that induction generator and also what we did is only
development of direct-to-drive synchronous generators as well and for
material steel glass fiber but now we added some elements and other materials
inside so we got composite structures and tapered pure steel tower as well in
the third stage in here so for turbine it's high towers long flexible blades
and active yaw smart turbine technology and for drivetrain it's permanent
magnet direct drive and some of them like semi-directive drive transmission
and for material it's changed right so here first and second stage is glass
fiber and for the third stage it's changed to carbon fiber this is a very
huge advancement and flexible high steel towers you can see it is over 120
meters and the steel concrete composite towers so it's totally different from
the previous tools and the fourth stage is now after the year of 2021 so we
We change from the land to sea.
So it's deep sea floating, offshore wind turbines.
And we use medium speed permanent magnet,
semi-direct to drive and direct to drive technology.
And for materials, the blade length,
it's getting longer, exceeds 120 meters.
So it's very huge.
And large scale application of carbon fiber,
protrusion process as well.
so for third and fourth stage steel carbon fiber okay and for the industry
chain upstream is mainly about raw materials and components and for the
midstream it's mainly about turbine manufacturing and integration we have
many corporations working on this so this is a data from last year like
Gold Wind. I don't know if you heard about these corporations. They have
installed capacity for 29 gigawatts and for aviation 20. Minyang Smart Energy and
Windy around 80. And the last one is Semi and DEC as well. They have around
30 gigawatts. And the downstream is wind farm development and operation. We
We also have some corporations like Huaneng in China,
also China Energy,
so which hold this conference training program, right?
In China, Huadian Corporation, China Datong Corporation.
This one is state power investment corporation as well.
And mainly they also do operation and maintenance as well,
like daily inspections, forge diagnosis,
and spare parts replacement as well how okay next is about photovoltaic this is
my research field okay so for photovoltaic technology we have too many
types right and we divided it into main three type so the first main type is
is silicon-based technology.
So I will just mention about some mainly ones.
The first one is PRC.
It's normally used dielectric preservation layers
like aluminum oxide and silicon nitride.
And for back contract, it can use interdigited back contract
as well.
And the second one, topcon.
It's very popular nowadays.
So we use ultra-thin tuner oxide layers
like silica oxide and heavily doped polysilicon layer.
For backcontract, normally like,
sorry, topcon backcontract
and the topcon hybrid backcontract.
And the third one is HGT.
This is also a very popular one.
heterojunction of crystalline silicon and also amorphous silicon. This one is like a
field, it's flexible and for crystalline silicon we know it's normally used
rigid substrate, right, so we combine them together and for back contract is hetero
back contract, this is hybrid passivated back contract and the hybrid
interdigitate that contract. This is the first type which is very mature and popular especially
before ten years ago maybe but nowadays we have many new technologies. The second one is
thin-beam technology. We have cadmium telluride. It has low manufacturing cost and commercially
mature but unfortunately the efficiency is not that high it's only around 20%
probably and for copper indium gallium selenide the second one it has high
theoretical efficiency but the real one the real efficiency is only around 23 I
see percent and it's compatible with flexible fabrication which is very good
And the third one is our star solar cells, gallium arsenide.
It has the highest conversion efficiency, not only in single junction, but also in multi-junction,
not only in concentrated, but also in non-concentrated.
So the highest efficiency for this one probably is three junction concentrated solar device,
which is around 47% the commercial efficiency.
It's pretty high.
But also, efficiency is high, cost is high, right?
Relatively expensive for this one.
And now we use it for space, so it's okay.
But for ground, it's too expensive.
And the last one, also a very popular one,
it's perovskite, also my research field.
it has high laboratory efficiency it's going up to 28% in this year and it has
very short process flow and a low cost as well okay so this is second type the
third type is tandem tandem also is a very emerging technology so how are you
going to get tandem cells first is perovskite together with silicon we have
two terminals, three terminals, four terminal tendon devices. Second is
perovskite only. So for top cell we use perovskite and the bottom cell still
perovskite. We got all perovskite tendon cells. It's just that the band gap is
different, right? And the third one is combined together with inorganic
compounds. So the cells, for example, like copper indium gallium selenide. So this
is three different types of tender technology which is also very popular nowadays okay
here we're gonna compare all these different technologies in this figure it's pretty obvious
in the top which one it is which one it is definitely gamma arsenide right i just mentioned
that no matter in single junction, multi-junction,
no matter, not only in concentrated, non-concentrated,
it always has the highest efficiency.
And the second one is also the popular one.
This laser doesn't work.
The second curve is perovskite.
So in the year of 2025, the efficiency is around 27.3,
but this year it's 28%.
it's growing very fast and the third type all this from the yellow one to this red one
these four curves are all about silicon-based and for silicon-based we have the highest one
about xbc okay and the next one is hgt heterojunction which is very popular and then
And then, which one, HGT, yeah, HGT, TOPCOM, it's also a very popular one.
The last one is the red curve, which is PRC.
Actually, PRC is very famous, like, many years ago, but now it has been replaced by TOPCOM.
So these are silicon-based, and after that is our inorganic compounds,
compounds, solar cells, except gallium arsenide, right?
So for inorganic compounds, the next one is
copper indium gallium selenide,
the last one is cadmium carbaride,
which is the lowest one, around 20%.
And this is the research to fabricate the device in here.
And after that, we're gonna compare the market share.
And you're going to say, all these are for which type?
The first type, right?
All of them are about silicon-based solar cells.
We cannot see inorganic compound or perovskite.
Why?
Because for perovskite, we just started the commercialization,
so we didn't have market share until now.
But for inorganic, for example, like gallium arsenide,
we also mentioned that it's mainly for spatial application so it's totally different from the
ground market share okay so when we compare it it's obviously here this one PRC this color it's
taking the main market share until the year of 2023 and it's going to the highest one in the
year of 2021 the market share is like 91.2 percent it's pretty high and but after 2023
it replaced by top count top count is like two percent only two percent in this year
but it's already 80 uh 87.6 percent in the year of 2025. why it's not like 90 or more than 90
because we have more and more technologies coming out right so for
example like HGT 3.3 and XPC 6.7 and also some others I'm not going to talk
about this is like less popular ones okay this is mainly about Proust guide which we
we are working on now for the industrialization development.
The production of rigid perovskite solar cells
in the industry has entered the mass production stage,
not for the flexible, just the rigid substrate.
10 pilot production lines of 100 megawatts or above
have been put into operation.
and 3 gigawatt scale production lines are under construction as well so this
is a very huge step. By the end of the year 2025, 9 megawatt scale ground
demonstration power stations using these single junction prospect modules have
been built with the largest single project reaching an installed capacity
around 8 megawatts so this is a table to compare the highest read highest
efficiency sorry for different solar cell types from different companies yeah
and on the top are all silicon based until here it's all silicon based and this
one is like inorganic compound, solar cells, and the last one is perovskite with
tantrum. Okay, so for example, for PRC, it has the highest efficiency around 24
percent, but not this year, it's like several years ago, around 2023. It's the
highest efficiency is from Longji company. It's a very famous photovoltaic
company in china they also have some other record like this one i mentioned earlier hpdc and hipc
the efficiency is around 28 which is pretty high for now especially for silicon based
and another one is this one cross guide with silicon tandem it's also pretty high certified
So we can compare it with single silicon crystal and single perovskite.
For single junction perovskite, the highest is 28.
For silicon, we can see from here, it's still 28, right?
But when we combine them together, it's going up like 35.
So it's a pretty good technology in the future.
And the second one is Topcon. I mentioned it's very popular, it's from Jinko Solar.
In China, the highest efficiency is around 27%, and also the other popular
one is HGT, also 27% from Trina Solar. Trina Solar is also a very famous company,
and they have another record holding for TPC, THPC solar cells and the other one
is for only for HPCs from GE solar or Goldstone Energy Company and these are
all about silicon-based and for inorganic solar cells like Longyan
Again, energy, yeah, I mentioned it earlier, right,
for cadmium telluride, it's a little bit, like,
not that satisfied.
The highest efficiency is only 20%,
and for copper indium gallium selenide, it's only 23%,
but for the star cell, gallium arsenide,
the highest is 3.7%.
It's from Durham Technology Company in China,
And for perovskite, the highest-holding institute is Hainan University, which happened this year in June, probably, it's like two months ago.
Okay, and for industrialization, especially for this tandem, right, we said it's emerging.
and we can see that before the year of 2023 actually we don't have any data for
module right this is just a laboratory we do it in the lab but we cannot have
modules but after the year of 2023 we have module efficiency and it's also
growing up steadily so it's very exciting this is from another Chinese
company that they made this tandem module so from this table we can divide
three stages for perovskite silicon tandem solar cells the first stage is
technology research and development stage we focused on distributed
applications of mass-produced perovskite modules no commercial tandem module
efficiency had been released so it's nothing in here the data and in the
second stage in from 23 to 24 it's large area pilot production stage in this
stage actually we got the module right so this company made continuous
industrialization process and planned its first gigawatt scale tandem module
based in Kunshan, Jiangsu province, scheduled for completion in this year.
And the third stage is in the year of 2025, its technology breakthrough stage.
stage, this is from Trina Solar, advanced low-shading conductive adaptive heat reduction
and photo management technologies improving both efficiency and power output.
So after the year of 2025, not only the companies but also like the university, like us, we
are happy to work on this tandem solar cell.
I also started it from last year, but until now, I haven't had any very exciting data,
but still working on it.
This is for biomass.
I think I will talk about it very quickly.
This is a road map, and it has three stages.
The third one is skill-up stage for biomass.
It started from the year of 2006.
we have some policies for that. It's for like benchmark on grid tariff for
guaranteed purchase by the power grid and subsidized for new projects based on
revenue availability. The second stage is coal generation stage. We combined heat
and power and the multi-source solid with the coal processing we achieved. The
The third stage is like carbon, negative stage.
So we have a blue paper for this,
on the development potential of zero carbon biomass energy
under the dual carbon goals.
So in this stage, declining competitiveness
of power generation, we have many other technologies, right?
And the sustainable aviation, biofuel, biomassing,
and green methanol as well okay and for biomass roadmap the first is waste to
energy incineration power generation for short term just the cost reduction and
the efficiency improvement is very simple and the medium term we're gonna
do multi force with the coal processing and for long term like fly ash
vitrification and also the other one is like carbon capture utilization and
storage carbon injection wells as well and the second is like agricultural and
And the forestry biomass power generation for short-term is full-scale combined heat and power.
This is the main thing.
And for medium-term, it's like fuel and equipment upgrading.
And for long-term, it's multi-energy complementary like microgrid and hydrogen production.
This is also very important.
And another one is biogas power generation.
for short-term ecological circular cogeneration and for medium-term like
high-value utilization and for long-term is deep power grid integration as well
okay the second topic is about breakthrough innovations in new energy
power generation the K innovations for power of a wind power generation I'm
gonna just talk about offshore because for land wind power it's we cannot say
like innovation maybe just the for offshore first is still about materials
do you guys still remember what I mentioned earlier for the materials of
offshore wind power or maybe land wind power we use glass fiber before right in
the first and second stage but after that we change to carbon fiber which is like more strong
and more light so carbon fiber protrusion technology it has low density and high tensile
strength and it reduces blade weight improves power generation efficiency and lowers tower load
It is also high stiffness, the blade tips are less prone to bending, and otherwise it has strong
fatigue and corrosion resistance as well. And for the generation of materials, the second one is we
use a recyclable thermal setting export resin. For this one, the materials, all the molecules,
it has specific cleavable chemical bonds and its condition triggered decomposition
which is good for the for the blade materials in future after the materials
generation we also have innovations for drivetrain and the power generation
technologies like for the first one is medium speed semi-directed drive
technology I talked about a little a bit earlier like it can balances generator
size weight and cost it can lower drive train failures and operation and
maintenance costs it has high efficiency across wide wind speeds also strong low
low-voltage drive-through and high-voltage drive-through
and grip support as well.
The second technology is like sliding bearing technology.
It has very high load bearing capacity,
lower nethally weight and foundation costs,
good vibration damping, no failure life limit.
This is very good.
The third is like evaporation cooling technology.
It has high cooling efficiency
and phase change cooling lowers auxiliary power use and stable and
uniform temperature as well this is also very important right no matter in wind
power and photovoltaic and also closed-loop protection against marine
corrosion this is also very important for offshore wind power and we have some
different types so if yesterday you didn't see very clearly here I'm going
to talk about almost all types of wind power so this is very uh obvious uh difference are there
this is like semi submersible floating platform and this is tension leg platform we can see the
difference right and for the advantagement for the first one it's very mature it has high maturity
strong stability and large megawatts, sorry, megawatt turbines.
But for the second one, we can see it's like very small, right?
But the capacity, it has like ultra large megawatts turbines, sorry, turbines as well.
Small motion and compact footprint as well.
So we compare these two.
And for this one, this is single-point mooring and here, multi-point mooring, these two.
And when we compare them, like single one, it has lower resistance, self-alignment, and better multi-rotor inflow.
And for the multi-point one, it has distributed loads, good redundancy, stable orientation.
so it's different it's depends on which side you're going to use it for right
application so and another one is high voltage then dynamic subsea cable
technology for example like these we've configuration it has a motion adaptive
design and the deep we've configuration free handling configuration as well the
The last one is for deep sea, far offshore,
and large-capacity applications, okay?
And here we have twin turbine floating system.
It has very high turbine density
and the shared foundation and mooring
and lower installation and operation and maintenance cost
forced battery capture by weather vaneing.
Also, another one is floating offshore substation.
This is like small station.
A small deep sea wind farms
and reduces fixed foundation works,
enables centralized planning
and offshore power collection hub as well.
That one.
This is the one we visited yesterday, right?
together with fishery so it's fishery wind integrated floating platform and
it's it has shared sea space utilization it combined wind power and marine
aquaculture together it has an ambidextrous aquaculture cage as well in the
bottom and smart armament monitoring the last one is floating high voltage direct current converter
platform it has very long distance power export actually i think this is very good for the
countryside right especially in this city because this city we have a big sea and lake so we can use
it for long-distance power export and the high-capacity transmission as well
supports GWAT scale basis reduces cable corridor pressure oh okay some projects
or examples the first one is China the three gorgeous lead project it achieved
grid connected in the year of 2021 it's the first floating offshore wind
platform in China so in the year of 2021 so we can see that it's only six years
or this is in December so it's like it's only five years past right but we
already have so many different types of offshore wind and the hub height we can
see it's 107 meters and for the rotor diameter around 158 meters and
And displacement volume for water is like 13,000 tons.
The second one is from China National Offshore Oil Corporation.
The project is Guanlan Project.
And it achieved the grid connected in the year of 2023.
And it is also China's first deep-sea floating platform.
so it's different from the others and offshore distance around 136 kilometers
and rotor diameter around 158 meters and the jack is 120 meters and for the
cable 5 kilometers and in-store capacity 7 megawatts it's not that large right
and for annual output around 22 million kilowatt hours the third one is the one
we visited yesterday right china energy sharing uh platform it's operated in the year of 2024
in june and it is china's first floating wind aquaculture platform also in the world i have
to say right and so the you probably already know all the details yesterday right so i'm gonna skip
give it. But this one, the fish cage volume is like 10,000 cubic meters, and it can contain
50,000 fish. And this fish, I heard that it's called big yellow fish. I don't know if I
translated it right or not. And it is quite expensive in China, and I had no idea about
that before. Yeah, I just know it yesterday. Okay, the last one is China's three gorgeous
pilot it's installed in this year like two months ago and it is the China's
first single turbine platform and we can see the offshore distance is not that
large it's like 70 kilometers and the depth is like higher than 50 meters
displacement volume is quite high right it's like the volume is like 24,000
tons when we compare it with which one? The first one. And the rotor diameter is also
very huge, 250. And the capacity is also high, right? Like 60 megawatts. And the estimated
annual output, because it's just like two months, more than two months, so the estimated
The estimated annual output is around 44 million kilowatt-hours, it's also very high as well.
And for photovoltaic, first, we're also going to talk about offshore photovoltaic.
So from here, we can see we have all different parts, different types, right?
like if you compare all of them you're gonna find that the first one is totally
different from the other one right where where is the difference here right it's
fixed right so this is a very major one and it's also like the earliest
development so it's pie or fixed offshore system it has high maturity and
wind or wind resistance synergizes with aquaculture salt pans this is the first
one and the second one from the picture we can see it's pontoon based floating
photovoltaic system it has minimal seabed disturbance broader water depth
range and the third one is semi submersible floating photovoltaic
platform actually I mentioned it a little bit earlier it has high
stability and wind or wind resistance supports tilted modules and the
equipment as well we can see it has more solar panels on the top compared with
the other ones right and the first one is with resistance resistant to non
overtoping floating photovoltaic platform is also different from all the
other eyes all the others right we can see that the distance between the water
surface is pretty high right for this one so for this one sorry it has less
sea water contact because it has larger distance and the lower corrosion and
and leakage risks.
And the fifth one, also a bit different.
The shape is different, right?
And it's not like very flat surface.
It's like a curve.
So for this one, it's flexible one.
So it use light weight and minimal material usage.
It's like a field, a very thin field.
It can reduce the wave impact and mooring loss.
and the last one is also the shape is a little bit different it's tension the
floating island photovoltaic platform so it has highly adaptable and modular and
eco-friendly composite materials okay and the other two like bifacial module
this is actually similar with the previous ones it's just solar panels is
different it's used by facial modules so it's unobstructed surface and the high reflection
and the higher energy yield per area of the last one so this one is similar with fishery wind right
the one we visited yesterday so we have fish cage in here as well and but the difference is like
for each solar panel we have a small fish cage and in the bottom so it's for
sorry mudflats aquaculture and the shallow seas and it has higher land and
water utilization as well increased economic benefits and lower aquaculture
energy cost as well. These are projects about offshore photovoltaic. We have so many projects,
I'm going to talk about it very quickly. The first is Hangzhou Tiantangling agrivoltaic
storage. This, we combine offshore PV together with agriculture, and it is the first batch
on grid and also we have complimentary energy storage as well around 51 megawatts and it's
installed it's achieved on grid in the year of 2023 installed capacity is around 488 megawatts
and the second one is Longyuan Tianjin Haijin salt photovoltaic project this is combined salt
together with Photovoltaic.
It's sort Photovoltaic fisheries all together.
Also equipped with 500 kilowatts station as well.
And so we see that for just one site,
we have three applications, right?
So this is a amazing one.
And the third is Zhongshan Dengbo Island Fishery Photovoltaic.
This is still like fishery Photovoltaic.
it has smart agriculture and this one is together with hydrogen energy storage as
well so photovoltaic hydrogen and energy storage all together for the production
of hydra is around 1500 okay and for complimentary sorry energy storage is
around 60 megawatts. And the next one is Dongshan Xincheng Offshore Photovoltaic.
It's combined with offshore wind power and for the wind speed is around 48
meters per second. And the Yantai Zhaoyuan fixed pile. This is a
very mature one and this one is fishery. Photovoltaic is also used pile fixed
photovoltaic which I mentioned earlier the first time the last one is Qingdao
refinery floating photovoltaic it's the first industrial operation floating
photovoltaic project in a fully seawater so this is put into use in the in last
year like one year back okay second innovation is about space photovoltaic
okay so we use gallium arsenide we have the experience is like first is basic
research and then for single junction multi junction and then triple junction
okay and then flexible gallium arsenide solar array for space and for commercial
satellite this is the environment in space so according to this we're going
to fabricate gallium arsenide and the characteristics is like efficient multi-band absorption and
ultra-seed and highly efficient compared with silicon-based and also high radiation resistance
it's better than silicon-based solar cells as well and wide temperature tolerance floatable and
deployable and these are the examples for China's spacecraft and also satellite
we all use gallium arsenide solar panels for power supply to the to the space for
space pv we also started a process ourselves and so like it has strong
light absorption long career diffusion length and high defect tolerance low
temperature fabrication so it's around 100 centigrade or 150 centigrade then we
can do the fabrication and tunable band gap wire composition so for the band gap
it can from 1.5 to 2.6 around and but it exists two main problems the first is
poor stability like it is sensitive to moisture heat light and bias so it's
like a big problem right because we put solar panels outside right so the second
Second problem is like low large area efficiency.
Now in my lab, we always fabricate the small area,
solar cells, devices.
So if we want to have the larger area,
the efficiency gonna decrease very fast.
So it's really hard for this one.
So how are we gonna solve all these problems?
We have so many strategies.
The easiest one is the first one,
compositional engineering. That means when we fabricate or prepare the perovskite materials,
we're going to change some molecules inside. For perovskite, we have A-side, B-side, X-side,
right? So we're going to choose different molecules to have different stability and
photovoltaic performance. And second one is, after we have the perovskite filled,
field what we're going to do we're going to do the passivation layer on the top right this is
uh interface passivation it can decrease the defect and the third one is active engineering
so we can put some materials or element inside of the precursor solution of prof guide as well
and another one to increase the stability this is especially for stability we can get
like low dimensional three-dimensional complex structures like 1d 3d or 2d 3d
right to improve the stability and this one is for this problem so we are
working on its large area fabrication process in this table on the right this
This is about the space application project
that happened before.
Like in the year of 2023,
Honghu second satellite, we use single junction.
For all these single junction solar cells,
the last one is, it's not showing very good.
Well, the last one is, I think it's,
it should be opened by office software,
then it's gonna be right.
this is WPS probably so these are all for single junction perovskite we have
it like application in space and the last one we cannot see it here it's for
tandem but I'm going to talk about it quite soon now so for perovskite silicon
tandem serals I mentioned earlier that we have two termational and three
three terminals, sorry, four terminals,
and the efficiency is like 35, 30, and 33
is pretty high, right?
This is like perovskite together with silicon.
This one is all perovskite.
On the top is wide bandgap perovskite.
The bandgap is around 1.67 to 1.7,
and in the bottom is narrow bandgap perovskite.
They are all perovskite,
and the band gap is around 1.2 to 1.26, probably.
And the last one is perovskite
together with copper indium gallium selenide.
So why we do tandem?
Because it's beyond the single junction.
Shockley-Queezer limit, right?
It can improve.
It has higher efficiency ceiling,
compatible with silicon photo industry,
industry and also strong potential for space and flexible applications.
So this year, it's still like several months ago, we had our Shenzhou number 23 satellite
man-made spacecraft launched into the space and we still use GaN for the main power supply
but we brought perovskite solar cell to the space as well for the experiment we
do real space extreme experiment testing and also efficiency degradation data
collection hope that we can get good data in future and start space
application for this another application for space PV is space solar power
the power station and the wireless power transmission is divided into two types.
One is concentrated, another one is non-concentrated.
So actually it's pretty simple for concentrated one, it's pretty easy.
We just use a small common cheap lens, right?
so put it on the top of our solar panel and then we can decrease the active area
of solar panels and the non-concentrating one is very normal and the general ones
so these are advantagement and we have several different projects for this I
don't have too much time left so for biomass I'm probably gonna
I'm gonna skip it, sorry.
For AI-driven, for CASB,
we have three steps for this.
The first one is we input data, right?
We have all different types of data,
like weather data, numerical weather prediction,
and the plant operation data, spatial environmental data
for space use, grid operation data,
market and load for system for market we have all different types of data we got
this and input it and the second step is data fusion and cleaning we first do
data cleaning and then anomaly detection also we probably gonna have missing data
right we do imputation as well and time synchronization and feature
engineering in the third step we have AI ready features like charm features it's
like hours holiday and the season sunrise sunset and weather like wind wind speed cloud cover
irradiation temperature and humidity the last one is operation operation features it's like
historical power equipment status and curcumin indicators so we had all this data and put it
into the machine right to calculate it and we can use all different models so
we have too many AI models models to use for forecasting for renewable energy we
divided into three types the first type is traditional machine learning
shallow models I'm gonna just talk about some of them probably like for example
For example, ANNBP is for non-linear mapping of wind speed power and irradiation power.
It is quite simple and easy to deploy.
And for example, the second one, SVM-SVR, is for small sample wind and solar power prediction.
It's quite stable under small data.
and we also have like random forest and the others the last one this one is
combined diverse models so it can improve the robustness this is the first
type the second type is like deep learning for temporal and spatial
features for example like the first one LSTM it's for ultra short term and
the short-term wind and photovoltaic forecasting it can handle time serious data but like the the
other one the third one tcn it's for long-term right long-term sequence prediction it has high
parallel efficiency and the other one like transformer it's for multivariate and multi-step
that power prediction, it is very strong modeling capability
for long sequence, so this is the first two different types.
And the third type, we combine them together.
We choose some of them, we call it hybrid models.
For example, we combine LSTM together with transformer,
so it's for short-term, day-ahead wind
of photovoltaic forecast and it has a short-term memory together with long
sequence attention and for CNN together with LSTM and transformer it's for cloud
charge and meteorology historical power fusion prediction as well so it's
combined space time attention all together and the third one is like GNN
and STGN is for multispatial and regional renewable energy forecasting and
the modeling spatial correlation as well. And the last one is PINN, it's for
wind or photovoltaic physical integration prediction. It can
improve credit credibility and generalization ability sorry um also for artificial integrated
driving renewable power forecasting it's also for engineering application we can get the ai
power forecasting results for example for renewable energy grid integration and dispatch
also for energy storage optimization and control virtual power plant aggregation
microwave dynamic response power electricity market trading and also
intelligent operation and maintenance and these are some projects in China
like the first one is Kuafu forecasting system for this one we mainly use high
high-risk numerical weather prediction
together with artificial intelligence.
It can serve higher than 600 renewable plants
and for wind or photovoltaic forecasting,
also for grid dispatch.
The second is from my hometown,
state-grade Xinjiang AI forecasting system.
They mainly use multi-aggressive AI forecasting
and the forecast accuracy actually is pretty high for wind power is around 96%
for photovoltaic it's around 98% and for big data renewable absorption as well
and the third one is from this province, Fujian province, it's for distributing PV
models and use grid based machine learning prediction and it's for
for country-level distributed photovoltaic,
distribution grid, and lightweight machine learning.
Let's see.
This one is Shenzhen Energy, Huawei.
Probably you guys know this company, right?
Huawei Cloud forecasting system.
They use Pengu, similar with that one.
This is Huawei Energy as well, sorry, Huawei company.
In here as well, they use Pamu-based power forecast,
and it can increase prediction accuracy.
It's like for wind, it can increase 10%.
For photovoltaic, it can increase 2%.
It's called called AI multi-entity forecast.
And for the other ones, it's mainly like this one.
It's for power system and market forecasting.
And this weather big model, together with AI,
is for prediction accuracy improvement around 3% to 5% the last one is power
using power sector foundation model for this one the forecast accuracy can
improve around 2.8% and for live model and 3D decision as well
okay so now the third topic is about new power system integration and the
application. Probably for this one, maybe you already have this topic, similar topic in the
first day. I'm not sure. Okay. So when we compare it for the traditional power system, right? So for
traditional power system, it's like generation always follow load. What kind of load we have,
we're going to build what kind of power generation system, right? And it's like one-way generation
side but we have more and more renewable energies coming so we definitely gonna
build new power system for this new power system it has high renewable
energy penetration and also multi-site coordinated flexibility management and
the most important one is interactive source grid load storage ecosystem we
we combine these four together.
I think in the first day's topic,
Professor Zhang also mentioned this, right?
Okay, so I'm not going to very detail for this,
for source grade load storage,
but it's very important for new energy system.
So the key features is like source follows load, right?
But load responds to supply
and the storage balances fluctuation.
remember what I mentioned earlier for PV power and wind power right it's like
it's not stable and great friendly operation smart coordination control as
well and K-fence it's like it has more renewables inside we can combine PV
biomass wind or maybe hydropower as well and it has lower costs and greater
greater flexibility and very reliable supply, okay?
For application, from generation side,
I mentioned earlier about this, right?
So for desert, for goby, bare land,
saline, alkaline land, for all of these,
we can use large-scale wind, solar bases.
The advantagement is like, for all these places,
is we have abundant wind and solar resources like my hometown and the lower land use constraints
concentrated development conditions and suitable for long distance bulk power delivery and then
in the right it's a project for this generation side i'm not talking about all of these but this
one. In the year of 2024, we had the first batch of large bases accelerated into operation. This
is very exciting, and we have a very important example in here. It's in Ningxia province,
it's Tanger Desert New Energy Base project. We combined photovoltaic desert restoration,
generation, energy storage, and ultra-high-voltage transmission all together.
This is a very important example.
And the planned capacity is like around 13 gigawatts, and developed by Longyuan Power.
Longyuan Power, remember?
Yesterday when we visited there, we saw for the wind power.
Okay.
All right.
thank you and the first three gigawatts of uh photovoltaic commissioned like uh 295 megawatts
okay i have less time but i still have many slides so for application sorry guys i will
talk very fast from now sorry so another application from grid side we actually have
the main two types the first type is like flexible high voltage direct
current transmission technologies we have all these four different types and
the second one is ultra high voltage direct transmission technology this is
very suitable for my hometown like west of China and in the right it's the
project for this grid side application and the other application is for the
load side so we have many flexible load right for different load we can do the
different work in here okay so I don't have time for the details sorry and from
the energy storage side for this one I can talk very fast because we're gonna
have presentation tomorrow and the day after tomorrow for visiting probably uh two types
the first one is short duration energy storage for uh frequency and the peak regulation like
we already familiar with right lithium ion battery sodium ion battery also we can we have flywheel
storage and together flywheel with lithium ion if it's short term and we also have like long
duration energy storage like flow battery storage and other like compressed
air energy storage okay this application is for smart micro grid and these are
all about the projects examples I will give talk about the first one in Beijing
And we combined 1.8 megawatts distributed photovoltaic, and for wind it's like 4.8 megawatts,
and for energy storage 2.9.
Also we have hydropower, like chilled, 3,000 chilled water storage, and 0.7 megawatts microtube.
okay and from virtual power plant application we have four stages the
first one is exploration stage started with demand response and the commercial
building load management the second is platform development and then we go to
the marketing the third stage the last one is standardization and the scaling
phase as well we improve the capacity like by 2027 it's gonna higher than 20
gigawatts and by 2030 higher than 50 this application is also very important
for green power direct connection it has dedicated lines clear traceability load
matched supply and the source load storage coordination as well the first
example also from China energy don't have steel it's it's a very famous one
and another one is computing power coordination we have China body and the
China that home project also we have it from Malaysia Johor green data center
clusters this is also a very good one and another way is from Thailand the
EEC computing power center cluster. It got the investment from Google around one
billion US dollars. It's like a very good one and there's a capacity for IT load
it's higher than 500 megawatts. This application is about system-friendly
renewable energy station. The example is from China's three gorgeous Wu Lan Cha Bu
green friendly green powder station demonstration project and the energy
storage is 30% of the installed capacity of wind and photovoltaic and another one
is the first batch of this is from National Energy Administration
administration new power system pilots like in different cities for this one is
directly in this city Fuzhou Fujian large-scale offshore wind power which
like we visited yesterday and okay sorry almost done probably this one you guys
gonna interested right but this one probably you will see it from tomorrow's
presentation the last one is policy I'm not going to talk about the policy the
policies for new energy development and policies for new energy consumption and
policies for new power system and also policies for electricity market so it's
very complicated right and also we have some electricity market mechanism as
well we have like ancillary service market sport market medium and long term
market so even for market we have so many different types and green electricity and
green certificate market this is a very important one so we have new energy electricity first and
trading right and after that we have issuance and the trading corporate green consumption as well
under the carbon footprint.
This is about the data for our green electricity and green certificate market, the data from
last year for power trading volume, issue volume, so what we get, and the trading volume
as well, okay?
Economic boundary, okay.
Okay.
That's a shame.
This is my research work.
Actually, I also want to talk about,
so I will talk very fast.
Neurosynthium solar cells.
Before, I worked on dye-sensitized solar cells
and some photoelectric functional materials.
And now, I mainly work on perovskite solar cells,
perovskite together with silicon,
also on perovskite tender,
and for child transporting layer and the preservation we use we also use some
simulation using this method and this is what we do first theoretical calculation
from simulation we calculate band structure charge density distribution
and the environmental stability in the first time to choose all the layers all
materials and in the second time we do experiment to get fabricates of film and
materials. This is like perovskite, normal three-dimensional. And this one is what I
mentioned, we combined 2D and 3D together to improve the stability. And that one is
for charge-transporting layer. And in the last step, we do device fabrication in
here. So we can see obviously this is the whole device from the bottom to the top
to the electrode this is a mechanism and this is another device structure so my
research field like the first one is even its profit we have different types
right so first one is lead-based the profit I'm not going to the
advertisement that I mentioned the stability is a big problem so now we
we focus on stability study, and we design and fabricate
the new devices, device optimization, new materials
employment.
So like several years ago, we mainly
used ALD for perovskite.
We can get very uniform and dense films
and functional layers.
This is another one for tin lead mixed perovskite.
it's not stable as well it even have very poor very bad stability compared
with previous one but why we still working on it why advantage ideal bandgap
right when we put tin inside we can we can change the percentage of tin inside
and then we can change the bandgap from 1.2 like different and also it's
suitable for tandem cells I mentioned that for bottom cell we use narrow band
gap solar cells right so we use this one so for stability we have all these
different strategies this is for solution strategy so for tin bead mixed
perovskite we also focus the first thing is stability we are not focused on
conversion efficiency why it's growing very fast and it's not that hard to get
high efficiency but for stability so that's why commercialization is not
stuck it and we don't have market share until now for proskite and this is some
research work for example like buffer layer I mentioned like we have in
interface preservation right so we use here silicon aluminum oxide and silicon
oxide together for the buffer layers this is a process the whole process how
we do it using ALD and a preservation layer is very similar with buffer layer
and also we use some active materials this is tin lead mixed the perovskite so
when we use materials it can combine with lead irons or tin irons to stop the
degradation. And for the passivation layer, in that one we also use
magnesium oxide as well. This is my academic achievement. And for the
books I wrote, even the title is in Chinese, but inside of the book it's
totally English. It's English books, but it's published in China, so the title is
in Chinese. This is my research collaboration with different
different universities. Okay, thank you.
Thank you. Questions?
Feel free to raise a question. Even if the professor and me not talk so much,
we still got time for the Q&A session. No rush.
Anyone? Thank you for the sharing.
I would like to ask, what is the minimum
wind speed before we know
So it is feasible to build a wind power plant in that area.
You mean land, right?
Minimum, probably around 40, because we
need higher wind resources for the wind power generation.